Register of the Nikolai F. Kostriukov Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Nikolai F. Kostriukov papers
1927-1985
2000C45
Hoover Institution Archives
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Correspondence, clippings, promotional materials, and photographs, relating to the General Platoff Don Cossack Chorus.
Kostriukov, Nikolai F., 1899-
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biography
N. F. Kostriukov was the long-time conductor of the General Platoff Don Cossack Chorus. He was born on 3 December 1898 in Tsymlianskaia stanitsa in the Don Cossack region. He studied mining engineering in Czechoslovakia in the 1920s, but never graduated because in 1927 he established the General Platoff Don Cossack Chorus, with which he toured the world for nearly half a century. His chorus became almost as well-known as that of Serge Jaroff.
Throughout the 1920s, the chorus toured Europe, and by the early 1930s it began making appearances in South America, Africa, and Asia. The chorus was based in Prague until 1939, when it moved to the United States. It recorded a number of albums on the Victor label. Kostriukov died in New York on 9 November 1987.
Chronology
1899 Born, Tsymlianskaia stanitsa, Don Oblast', Russia
1927 Established Gen. Platoff Don Cossack Chorus
1943 Married Apolinariia Petrovna Kostriukova
Scope and Content Note
Nikolai F. Kostriukov was the conductor and director of the General Platoff Don Cossack Chorus, and these papers reflect the history of that chorus, its tours and concerts. Materials include concert programs, reviews, photographs, and correspondence.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco, as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
General Platoff Don Cossack Chorus; Choral societies--United States.; Russia.; Russians--United States.; United States.
- Biographical File, 1930-1950 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Award and questionnaire, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Correspondence, 1928-1985 (Box 1)
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent
- Writings, 1970 and undated (Box 1)
  Notes on the history of the chorus and its tours, and letter to the editor, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- General Platoff Don Cossack Chorus File, 1927-1972 (Box 1-3)
  Advertisements, promotional materials, scrapbooks and other matter on the chorus arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Photographs, 1932-1948 and undated (Box 3)
  Twenty-six photos depicting Kostriukov and the chorus in various venues
- Miscellany, 1939 (Box 3)
  Autographed musical notes presented to Kostriukov
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1930-1950 (Box 1)
  General note
  See also GENERAL PLATOFF DON COSSACK CHORUS
  - Award, bestowed upon Kostriukov by Ahmad Pasha Bey, ruler of Tunisia, 1930 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Biographical questionnaire for Museum of Russian Culture, 1950 (Folder 1: 2)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1928-1985
  See also GENERAL PLATOFF DON COSSACK CHORUS/Scrapbooks
  - Artsybasheva, E., 1928 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Kojanovich, Basilio, 1930 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Krasnov, Petr N., 1934-1938 (Folder 1: 5)
    Includes autographed photo attached to final letter
  - Museum of Russian Culture, 1985 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Semenov, G. M., 1938-1939 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Zuev, A. V., 1939 (Folder 1: 8)
- WRITINGS, 1970 and undated
  - Letter to the editor, 1970 October 27 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Notes on the history of the chorus and its appearances in various countries (Folder 1: 10)
- GENERAL PLATOFF DON COSSACK CHORUS FILE, 1927-1972
  - Addresses in honor of Kostriukov and the chorus, 1929-1938 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Advertisements for concerts. (Folder 1: 12)
    Includes posters
  - Clippings about Kostriukov and the chorus, including reviews, 1937-1972 and undated (Folder 1: 13)
  - Concert programs and promotional materials (Folder 1: 14)
  - List of tours and concerts given from, 1927 to 1972 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Scrapbooks. (Box-folder 2: 1-4)
    Include advertisements, clippings, correspondence, programs, promotional materials, reviews and other material
  - Scrapbooks (Box-folder 3: 1-3)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1932-1948 and undated (Folder 3: 4)
  Twenty-six photos of the chorus appearing in various venues. Includes autographed photos
- MISCELLANY, 1939 (Folder 3: 5)